peaceoneday.org 2019-09-25

# Privacy Policy | Peace One Day

##### Introduction

POD values your privacy. This Privacy Policy gives you specific information on how POD treats personal information (such as name, date of birth, email address, mailing address, telephone number(s), etc) submitted by you to POD via the Website (referred to herein as “Personal Information”). This Privacy Policy shall be deemed to be incorporated into the Terms and Conditions and sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”) the data controller is Peace One Day Limited whose registered office is located at Highfield Court, Tollgate, Chandlers Ford, Eastleigh, Hampshire, SO53 3TY.

##### What information does POD collect

If you do not register with POD via the Website, then the information that POD collects from you will be limited. POD logs your IP address in order to help diagnose problems with our server, administer the Website and track usage statistics. Your IP address may vary each time you visit, or it may be the same, depending on the type of internet connection that you access the Website with. Either way, it would be extremely difficult for us to identify you through your IP address, and POD makes no attempt to do so. If you reach the Website by clicking on a link or advertisement on another internet website, then POD also logs that information. All of this information is collected and used only in the aggregate; that is, it is entered into our database, where POD may use it to generate overall reports on our visitors, but not reports about individual visitors. Please note that the Website uses what are commonly known as “cookies”. Cookies are small pieces of information that browsers store on your computer’s hard drive. POD uses cookies to recognise users who have already visited the Website, allowing those users to speed up future activities on the Website by offering functionality such as persistent shopping carts. Cookies also enable POD to measure aggregate usage and traffic to areas of the Website and specific offerings, which assists POD in providing content that best meets our users’ preferences. By default, your browser is probably set to accept cookies, however you can reconfigure your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to refuse cookies, some areas of the Website may not function correctly. If you choose to register with POD, you will be able to take advantage of all the features of the Website. If you register with POD or purchase goods or services through the online shop, POD will collect Personal Information from you in addition to the non-Personal Information described above. The information POD collects from you may vary, but POD only collects the information that you enter into the forms on the Website.

How POD uses your Personal Information

Your Personal Information may be used in the following ways:

  * to display your name, age (if provided), country, category of affiliation (e.g. individual, school, corporation or other) and your Peace Day commitment on the Website;
  * to fulfil your requests for products and services, such as the content available through the Website and newsletters and other electronic alerts;
  * to allow us to process your donation;
  * to send you information you agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to you;
  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;
  * to communicate with you regarding transactions conducted through the Website (including the online shop), any co-branded internet website or for other internal purposes;
  * to analyse usage patterns of the Website in order to determine which areas our users find most valuable to them and to evaluate ways to improve the Website; and
  * in the manner set out in the section of this Privacy Policy headed “With whom is your Personal Information shared” (see below).

We may, pursuant to any consent given by you, also permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these.

##### With whom is your Personal Information shared

POD may share your Personal Information:

  * with its affiliated entities, including for the purpose of such affiliated entities notifying you from time to time about their products and services which they believe you may find valuable or of interest (if you would rather not receive this marketing information, please contact POD using the contact details listed below);
  * with third party vendors, suppliers and subcontractors (such as website hosting companies and credit card / payment processors) for the purpose of providing you with products and services, including, without limitation, the Website, the Website Content and the Services;
  * in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  * when required by law, such as when POD responds to subpoenas, court orders or legal process or to protect the rights, property or safety of POD, our customers, affiliates or others; and
  * when POD believes it reasonably necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or improper activities, suspected fraud, potential threats to the rights, property or safety of POD, its users or others, or violations of the Terms and Conditions of this Privacy Policy,

wherever such persons are located in the World, including, for example, the United States of America. Please be aware that the laws of most countries outside the European Economic Area are generally not regarded as providing the same level of protection for Personal Information as those of countries making up the European Economic Area (ie such countries’ laws are generally not regarded as providing “adequate” data protection as contemplated under Article 25 of the European Union’s Data Protection Directive (95/46/EC)). As noted above, POD may collect non-Personal Information about you, such as the type of internet browsers you use or the internet website from which you linked to the Website. You cannot be identified from this information and it is only used by POD to assist in providing an effective service on this Website. This information (together with Personal Information that has been aggregated with other information so that you are no longer identifiable from it) may be supplied by POD to prospective partners, advertisers and other reputable third parties, but on an aggregated and anonymous basis (ie with no personally identifying information).  **Where we store your personal data**  The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. POD will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.  **Security**  POD has adequate security measures in place to protect against loss, unauthorised access, misuse, alteration and improper disclosure of the Personal Information you provide to POD, which include maintaining Personal Information on a secure server behind a firewall and encrypting Personal Information during transmission and storage. However, no computer system or information can ever be fully protected against every possible risk and POD does not guarantee the security or integrity of the Personal Information you disclose online. Notwithstanding POD’s security measures, you should be aware that when you submit Personal Information to the Website over the Internet, the information may travel over many systems that are not under POD’s control and are not completely secure.

##### Opting-out of receiving messages from POD

POD will only send you unsolicited emails if you have given POD permission to do so. If POD sends you unsolicited emails, the email will enable you to register an opt-out to receiving other emails from POD.

##### Children

The safety of children is very important to POD. No information should be submitted to or posted on the Website by children under the age of 13 without prior parental consent.

##### Your rights with respect to your personal information

You have a right under the Act to a copy of all the Personal Information about you held by POD. You also have a right to correct any errors in that information. You also have a right to prevent POD from using your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes.

##### Contacting POD

If you have any questions, concerns, comments or complaints in respect of the Website, the Website Content or the Services or wish to amend any errors in the Personal Information that you have provided to POD, please contact POD using the contact details provided below: Email: [web@peaceoneday.org](mailto:web@peaceoneday.org) Fax: + 44 (0)20 8334 9900 Telephone: +44 (0)20 8948 0545 Postal address:  **Peace One Day Ltd**  St. George’s House 15 St. George’s Road Richmond Surrey TW9 2LE United Kingdom
